ALI HAMMOUD

■ ali_hammoud_1994@hotmail.com

**** +961 79 146 800

Lebanon -Beirut

SKILLS

- IT Skills:
 - CompTIA (A+, Network+, Security+)
 - Cisco
 - o Technical troubleshooting
- E-commerce:
 - Product research
 - Ad writing
 - WordPress (WooCommerce)
- Programing Skills:
 - o HTML, CSS.
- Professional Skills:
 - o Team Player
 - Decision maker
 - o Time management
 - Very Organized

Languages:

- Arabic Native
- English Upper-intermediate
- French Intermediate

EDUCATION

Lebanese International University

Beirut - 06/2019

Master of Science: Computer and Communication Engineering

- Graduated with 3.06 GPA
- Coursework in Advanced Networking, Advanced Architecture of MIPS 32 and 64-bit, Wireless Communication, Cryptography & Advanced Computer Security and Fiber Optics
- Thesis: Implementation of a Digital Reconstruction Stage in Sigma Delta ADC Modulator for SDR Receivers. The main goal is to increase the frequency of the oscillators with minimum SNR, to be able to be used in advanced communication technologies

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated and highly skilled NOC Engineer with 2 years of experience in monitoring and resolving issues in the network and system environment, and more than 3 years of experience in the IT field. I am shifting my career path to web development, willing and trying to learn programming skills and new technologies related to web development. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements.

WORK HISTORY

CSC BANK – NOC Engineer

Beirut 10/2019 - Current

- Monitor network systems for performance issues and find ways to optimize a computer system by utilizing SolarWinds, PRTG, Whatsup Gold and Vsphere Vmware.
- Troubleshoot issues presented by clients over a variety of contact methods. If a solution cannot be found or if the issue is outside the scope of the NOC Support Engineer, the problem is escalated to third-party vendors, field engineers or other relevant teams.
- Track and report on all issues with full documentation to increase the knowledge base of the NOC Support Engineer and all relevant staff members so that future issues are resolved more efficiently
- Manage user information using active directory to add new employee/customers, Lock/Unlock - Enable/Disable and deletion of user accounts.
- Responsible for 24/7 monitoring the electricity of the company include EDL, Generators, and UPS, and report any issue that occur to the facility team

Freelancer- Wordpress Developer

Beirut 10/2021 - Current

- Design and implement websites for companies using the WordPress creation tool.
- Meeting with clients to discuss website design and function.
- Designing & building the website front-end and conducting website performance tests
- Designing and managing the website back-end including database and server integration.
- Analyzing website performance and troubleshooting errors
- Conducting WordPress training with the client.
- Ensuring high-performance and managing all the technical aspects of the CMS

Freelancer - IT Engineer

Beirut 10/2020 - 08/2021

- Selling PCs or laptops and PCs or Laptops component.
- Repairing PCs and Laptops and diagnose home networks.
- Completed customer requested change requests including PC equipment relocation, application software upgrades, PBX/telephony change requests and desktop computing upgrades.

EDUCATION

Lebanese International University Beirut – 06/2017

Bachelor of Science: Computer Engineering

- · Graduated with 3.25 GPA
- Dean's Honor List Fall 2015, Fall 2016 and Fall 2017
- Coursework in Calculus III, OOP Java Language, Communication Networks using Cisco Technology, Basics Linux Commands, Digital Logic Design, Mobile and Web Development and Data Structures and Analysis of Algorithms
- Senior Project: Instructor Attendance System. The main goal is to automate the attendance of the instructor by calculating the range of the WIFI that the phone will connect to with the position of the instructor in the building, and by using a manual system using a Raspberry PI

WORK HISTORY

ICC (Contractor in AUBMC)—IT Engineer

Beirut 06/2018 - 01/2020

- Install and configure IT devices including but not limited to (PC, Monitor, Printer, scanner, Mobile cart).
- Update inventory sheet for every device.
- Relocate some specific IT devices
- Report progress daily to Supervisor.
- Maintenance the network, resolve network issue, and some basic active directory.

Saint Severius School – IT Engineer

Beirut 09/2017 - 06/2018

- Responsible for the network of the school and maintenance for all the computer in the school
- Help other instructors to use the computer, and tutor all the classes of the school the basics of using Microsoft office.
- Removed malware, ransomware and other threats from laptops and desktop systems.
- Install and configure IT devices including (PC, Monitor, Printer)

Certification of Completion

- Certification of Completion for CCNA 200-301 by using CBTNuggets videos, between Jan 2020 till March 2020.
- Certification of Completion for A+ (220-1001 and 220-1002) by Total Seminars - Mike Meyers (Udemy), between March 2020 till April 2020.
- Certification of Completion for CCNA Routing and switching in CNS CO. between Feb 2019 till March 2019.
- Certification of Completion for MTCNA by Maher Haddad (Udemy), between June 2020 till July 2020.
- Certification of Completion for Microsoft Windows Server 2019 -Hands-on Training Part I & II by Prof. K (Udemy), between June 2020 till August 2020.